# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天我让我伯爷留了2根猪后脚回来卤
Today, I asked my uncle to leave me two pork hind legs for braising
# 这个猪脚杆有好重安
How heavy are these pork legs?
# 五斤多6斤的样子
More than 5 jin, about 6 jin-ish (1 jin = 500 grams)
# 这个我伯爷已经把它烧了 烧了也洗干净了
Uncle has already burned it. Burned it and cleaned it
# 本来是说他要拿去卖掉的
He was supposed to sell them
# 你不打电话我都卖了
They're sold if you didn't call me
# 你把这个勾哈嘛 你来
Could you hook it away?
# 诶呀
Eh-ya
# 你不专业的话你还勾不掉
You can't hook it away if you ain't professional
# 嗯 这是我伯爷的专业
Yeah, that's my uncle's professionalism
# 慢点哦
Careful
# 不关事 这个刀未必还难得到我呀
Doesn't matter. Dis knife ain't a problem
# 划断吗
Cut it through?
# 嗯 划断嘛划断
Hmm, cut it through
# 好
Alright
# 可以了
Good
# 这个猪脚没有抽筋噶
We haven't remove the trotter tendon?
# 没有抽筋这不是那根大筋呀
Nope. Ain't dat da big tendon?
# 这个筋在这里 这个筋大家看一下
This is the tendon. Let's take a look
# 扯得出来不
Can we pull it out?
# 扯得出来 好生点划到手
Pull it out. Be careful, don't hurt your hand
# 这个筋像那个葱白一样
The tondon is like a scallion white
# 像葱一样 是不是跟葱葱一样
Like a scallion... Isn't it like a scallion?
# 嗯
Hmm
# 今天这是用我们自己这个卤料来
Today, we're gonna use our master stock bag
# 我们这个卤料直接卤就行了
We can stew directly with it
# 一包卤料的话加三斤这个东西（食材）
One master stock bag is good for cooking 3 jin (of ingredients)
# 所以我们6斤多的猪脚弄2包
So for 6 jin of trotters, we use 2 bags
# 刚好差不多
Dat's about right
# 有很多粉丝之前在问这个卤料包买回去怎么用
Many followers bought this bag, and asked how to use it
# 现在这一期视频就跟大家分享
So we're gonna share it in this video
# 我们打开了这个之后要检查一下这个线这里
After opening, we need to check the thread here
# 不要让它流出来
Don't let it go out
# 然后给它放好
Then set them aside
# 吃得辣不
Can you eat spicy?
# 这天气大了就少整点海椒撒
Da weather is hot, less chili
# 这个海椒不是很辣
These chili peppers are not too chili
# 不是很辣 那就可以
Not too chili? Good
# 我们把它倒进去
Let's pour it in
# 好
Alright
# 然后这个卤料包拆出来把辣椒这些倒出来
So we open the package, and pour out the chili
# 就放到一起
And put them together
# 切点姜片
Chop some ginger
# 切长一点 2根葱就可以了
Chop longer chunks. Two scallions are enough
# 然后就差不多了就可以用了
Then it's enough. Good to go
# 然后我们卤这个东西的时候就只要加这个就行了
Later when we braise, we just need to add this
# 盐都不用放
No salt is needed
# 然后一包卤料放4斤水
And for each bag, we add 4 jin of water
# 2包的话就放8斤水
For two bag, 8 jin of water
# 然后慢慢地去卤这个猪脚
And then simmer the trotters
# 来嘛 四伯爷帮我端嘛
Come on. Help me take it, uncle
# 好 卤之前先把猪脚焯下水
Alright. Before braising, we need to parboil the trotters
# 把这个猪脚冷水下锅焯水
Parboil the trotters in cold water
# 你看 这个全是血沫
Look, it's full of blood scum
# 我们这个姜葱油炒香了之后
Now we've make the ginger and scallion oil aromatic
# 把姜葱炒香了开始放水
Add water after it's aromatic
# 水的话大概放个8斤多都可以
We add about 8 jin of water
# 8斤9斤都可以
8 jin or even 9, doesn't matter
# 因为这个要卤很久
Because it takes a long time to cook
# 所以如果放9斤的话就可以弥补一下
If we add 9 jin, it's going to compensates
# 等下煮的时候蒸发的水份
the water vaporized during cooking
# 好 可以放水了
Alright, water in
# 我们先把猪脚放下去 放上这个水漫过这个猪脚
We put in the trotters, and add water to cover them
# 好 差不多了
Alright, good
# 然后再把我们的这个卤料包放下去
Then we put in the master stock bags
# 辣椒
Chili pepper
# 我们这个卤料包里面盐还有颜色都是配好的
We have salt and coloring in the bag. Everything well prepared
# 大家可以看一下这个出来的颜色
We can take a look at the color it gives
# 然后我们这个烧开了之后
And after it's brought to a boil
# 就开小火慢慢卤它40分钟
We simmer it for 40 minutes
# 卤40分钟就可以拿出来吃了
Simmer for 40 minutes, then it's good to serve
# 这中间不有加盐不用加糖
No salt, no sugar added while cooking
# 什么都不用加
Nothing to add
# 就只要水和姜葱 加点油
other than water, ginger, scallion and some oil
# 然后就可以放原材料下去卤了
Then we can put in the ingredients to braise
# 然后卤味这个烧开了之后 卤水烧开之后
After the stock is boiling,
# 也要打一下这个血沫
skim off the blood scum again
# 这个可以卤鸡鸭
Dis works for chicken, duck
# 所有东西都可以卤
Works for everything
# 可以卤牛肉 卤猪 卤鸡鸭兔都可以卤
Works for beef, pork, chicken, duck, rabbit, everything
# 只要你想得出来卤的都可以丢下去卤
Everything you can think of, dump it in and braise
# 这个颜色都出来了
We've brought out the color
# 好了 我们这个已经卤了40分钟
Alright, we've cooked for 40 minutes
# 然后小火卤了40分钟
Simmered for 40 minutes
# 刚才已经泡了大概20分钟了
And soaked for about 20 minutes
# 现在我把它重新烧开了就可以捞出来了这个猪脚
Now I'm gonna re-boil it, then we can take out the trotters
# 大家可以看一下这个颜色 颜色非常的漂亮
Let's take a look at the color, which is very pretty
# 诶呀
Eh-ya
# 然后剩下的卤水我们把它的渣全部捞干净
And then we scoop out all the residue in the master stock
# 然后凉了之后可以放到冰箱里面
After it cools down, we can store it refrigerated
# 下一次又可以卤
And use it next time
# 可以反复卤个两三次没问题这个卤水
The master stock can be reused for a couple of times
# 好 关火
Alright, fire off
# 好了 现在我们来试一下
Alright, now let's have a try
# 用刀割点下来尝一下味道怎么样
Slice a bit and see how it tastes
# 我给你割一坨肥一点哈四伯爷
Let me give you a fatty slice, uncle?
# 要得啊 小坨点 割大坨了
Yup. Smaller, dat's too big!
# 来嘛 这里有碗
Here you are. We have a bowl here
# 我来给你割你尝哈看
Let me slice it for you. Have a try
# 嗯 卤耙了
Hmm, it's braised soft
# 耙了是不
Is it soft?
# 嗯
Yeah
# 我们这个所有的卤味啊卤出来了之后
After cooking finishes, all the braised food
# 家庭操作的卤味拿出来了之后
All the home-version braised food, after cooking
# 它会受到氧化
It gets oxidized
# 然后颜色会变得深一些
And the color turns darker
# 如果你炒糖色掌握得不好的话
Say if we haven't fully mastered making caramelized sugar
# 用糖色卤出来一会儿就会
Food braised with the caramelized sugar will...
# 你这个大了我来割
You got it too big, gimme da knife
# 你来割啊 来嘛
OK, you slice it
# 我来割坨小点的
I'll make a smaller slice
# 就用手抓着吃
Eat it with your hands
# 如果我们家庭里面炒糖色的
So if we make caramalized sugar at home
# 控制不好糖色的成色 卤出来一会就要黑这个
and fail to control its quality, the food turns dark very soon
# 黑了也很正常
It turns dark, which is normal
# 来嘛 你吃这个蹄筋嘛
C'mon, have dis tonden
# 蹄筋呀这个是
Is this a tendon?
# 那不是蹄筋咋子
Ain't it a tendon?
# 又脆有香
Crunchy and flavorful
# 真的是很脆
That's really very crunchy
# 是啊 那个蹄筋安逸得很
Yeah, dat tendon is very nice
# 这个皮子还多安逸
Da skin is so nice
# 是不
Is it?
# 是啊
Yeah
# 这个皮子很香
Da skin is very flavorful
# 我们这个卤料包你看是像这个样子的
The master stock bag. This is what is looks after after cooking
# 卤了之后把它捞出来放凉了之后放到冰箱里面
After cooking, we can take it out, cool it down, and store it refrigerated
# 第二次可以接着卤
And use it next time
# 你看这个水 里面的这个香料都还多香
Look at the water. The spices are still so aromatic
# 还可以卤一两次
Can be reused for a couple of times
# 就是跟它整那个懒人排骨差不多嘎
It's like da "Lazy Man's Pork Rib"?
# 哦喔有点像
Oh, yeah
# 拿这个袋子放在里面
Just put a bag there
# 这些放在里面就可以卤了
Put things in da bag, then you can cook
# 这个效果的话其实还（不错）
The results are acually... (good)
# 效果还是很好
Da results are very good
# 效果还是不错
The results are pretty good
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright, that's all for this video
# 这个很方便的
Dis is very convenient
# 跟大家推荐这个懒人卤料
I recommend this "Lazy Man's Master Stock Bag" to you guys
# 懒人卤料 硬是懒人卤料
Lazy man's bag... What a lazy man's bag
# 好啦 就到这里了 拜拜
Alright, that's all. Bye bye
# 好方便嘛
So convenient